{
  "java": {

    "questions": [{
      "id": 1,
      "question_type": "fib",
      "question": "Java is a ______ Oriented language",
      "answer": "object",
      "hint": "Java works around structures called objects"
    },
      {
        "id": 2,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The correct syntax to print hello world is: A. Print(hello world) B. Print(“Hello world”); C. System.out(“Hello world”); D. System.out.print(“Hello world”)",
        "answer": "D",
        "hint": "You want to call the Systems “out” method and “print” it to the console"
      },
      {
        "id": 3,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "What primitive data structure holds a non-floating point number?",
        "answer": "int",
        "hint": "The primitive for an integer"
      },
      {
        "id": 4,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "When writing a String backslash-____ is an escape sequence for a new line A. u, B. q C. n D. s",
        "answer": "C",
        "hint": "To call a new line, you’d want to use this escape character"
      },
      {
        "id": 5,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Java runs on the Java ____ Machine A. Virtual B. Async C. Old D. Digital",
        "answer": "A",
        "hint": "Java is run using a virtualized machine"
      },
      {
        "id": 6,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "Java was developed at a company called ___ Microsystems",
        "answer": "sun",
        "hint": "Some might say this company rose everyday, much like something in the sky"
      },
      {
        "id": 7,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "A line of java ends with a: A. ; B. > C. // D. =",
        "answer": "A",
        "hint": "You use this when the line is complete, not when its “semi” done"
      },
      {
        "id": 8,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "When a double is converted to an int, it is round in which direction?",
        "answer": "down",
        "hint": "Which way is the ground?"
      },
      {
        "id": 9,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Question: To make a comment in java, you would use: A. <! B. // C. – D. ~",
        "answer": "B",
        "hint": "This would “slash” out the comment"
      },
      {
        "id": 10,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "In a method header, the  ____ keyword indicates that the method will not return anything",
        "answer": "void",
        "hint": "It will return void"
      },
      {
        "id": 11,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "To increment the variable: int i=0; you would use: A. i++; B. I add C. I inc; D. I+2;",
        "answer": "A",
        "hint": "++ adds one to a value"
      },
      {
        "id": 12,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "The modulus operator returns the _____",
        "answer": "remainder",
        "hint": "It is not the Quotient"
      },
      {
        "id": 13,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "A function in Java is referred to as a _____",
        "answer": "method",
        "hint": "It is a “method” of doing something"
      },
      {
        "id": 14,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "Java is a _____ threaded language A. Hard B. Single C. Invisible D. Multi",
        "answer": "D",
        "hint": "Java can use “multi”ple threads"
      },
      {
        "id": 15,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "The assignment operator in Java is: A. – B. ~ C. = D. .",
        "answer": "C",
        "hint": "Remember to drink vitamin C"
      },
      {
        "id": 16,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "In java, arrays start an an index of: __",
        "answer": "0",
        "hint": "The number zero"
      },
      {
        "id": 17,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "To multiply two numbers, you would use the __ operator",
        "answer": "*",
        "hint": "It is not “x”"
      },
      {
        "id": 18,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "From the Java Standard Library, you would use the ____ keyword to add it to your project A. Import B. Pkg C. Add D. Library",
        "answer": "A",
        "hint": "You need to import it"
      },
      {
        "id": 19,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "To initialize an array you would declare the type and this operator: A. { } B. [ ] C. < > D. = =",
        "answer": "B",
        "hint": "An array could be kept in a square"
      },
      {
        "id": 20,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "To create a new Java class, you would use the keyword _____",
        "answer": "class",
        "hint": "You may have learned this in class"
      }
    ]
  },

  "golang": {

    "questions": [{
      "id": 1,
      "question_type": "mc",
      "question": "An acceptable declaration of an array using Go is: A. array[5] integers B. var arr [10]string C. string[5]; d. 5 string[]",
      "answer": "B",
      "hint": "Arrays get declared as a var first"
    },
      {
        "id": 2,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "What is the operator to decrement a number by one?",
        "answer": "--",
        "hint": "It is the same as the decrement operator in java"
      },
      {
        "id": 3,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "What is the keyword to add a package to a golang file?",
        "answer": "import",
        "hint": "Similar to buying a foreign object and shipping it to the United States, you have to import it"
      },
      {
        "id": 4,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "What is the package that must be importted to use any formatted I/O with golang? A. string B. io C. String D. fmt",
        "answer": "D",
        "hint": "How could you abbreviate formatted?"
      },
      {
        "id": 5,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "What is the keyword to declare a function?",
        "answer": "func",
        "hint": "Abbreviate the word function"
      },
      {
        "id": 6,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "The return type of a function comes before or after the function name and parameters?",
        "answer": "after",
        "hint": "It does not come before"
      },
      {
        "id": 7,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "What package has to be imported to get the current time? A. time B. clock C. Sundial D. Hourglass",
        "answer": "A",
        "hint": "You only need to get the time"
      },
      {
        "id": 8,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "What is the operator to increment a number by one?",
        "answer": "++",
        "hint": "It is the same as the increment operator in java"
      },
      {
        "id": 9,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "The type of parameter comes after or before the variables name?",
        "answer": "After",
        "hint": "It is not before"
      },
      {
        "id": 10,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "What is the operator for a short assignment? A. := B. = C. == D. ===",
        "answer": "A",
        "hint": "It uses a colon"
      },
      {
        "id": 11,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "What is the modulus operator? A. & B. % C. @ D. /",
        "answer": "B",
        "hint": "It is the same as the modulus operator in java"
      },
      {
        "id": 12,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "What is the basic type of a variable that can only be true or false? A. boolean B. bool C. truefalse D. bit",
        "answer": "B",
        "hint": "How could you abbreviate boolean?"
      },
      {
        "id": 13,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "An int declared but not initlaized is given a value of: A. 0 B. zero C. null d. one",
        "answer": "A",
        "hint": "An int is numeric"
      },
      {
        "id": 14,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "The loop supported by golang is a ___ loop",
        "answer": "for",
        "hint": "It is a loop supported in java and not a while loop"
      },
      {
        "id": 15,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "A statement with cases is called a ______ statement",
        "answer": "switch",
        "hint": "It is the same as it is in java"
      },
      {
        "id": 16,
        "question_type": "mc",
        "question": "An If statement needs to be surrounded by: A. () B. // C. <> D. {}",
        "answer": "D",
        "hint": "Only curly braces are required"
      },
      {
        "id": 17,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "A _____ statement makes the function wait until the function it is within runs first",
        "answer": "defer",
        "hint": "It needs to be deferred"
      },
      {
        "id": 18,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "A _______ holds the memory address of a value?",
        "answer": "pointer",
        "hint": "It is the same as in C"
      },
      {
        "id": 19,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "What is a collection of fields, similar to an object, in golang?",
        "answer": "struct",
        "hint": "It is the same as in C"
      },
      {
        "id": 20,
        "question_type": "fib",
        "question": "Golang was created at which popular tech company?",
        "answer": "google",
        "hint": "Think of the first two letters of golang and your most used search engine"
      }
    ]
  }
}